# MANUEL CASANOVA



manucasanova@hotmail.com



604 723 3155



www.manucasanova.com

Vancouver, B.C.



https://www.linkedin.com/in/manuel-casanova



manuelcasanova

### **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Developer with a background in teaching foreign languages (5+ years of experience) and hotel management (10+ years of experience). Highly organized. Will-do attitude, willing to accept challenges and to learn the necessary skills to succeed. Dispute resolution. Multilingual. Experience working in multicultural environments both in the private and non-profit sectors.

# **SKILLS**

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

FRAMEWORKS, LIBARIES AND ENVIRONMENTS **TESTING** 

SYSTEMS, CMS, AND DATABASES

JavaScript, Ruby, HTML, CSS

NodeJS, ReactJs, Ajax, Express, EJS, jQuery, Bootstrap, ActiveRecord, Rails, SASS

Storybook, Cypress, RSpec, Jest, Mocha, Chai

SQL, Git, PMS (Property Management Systems) – Hotel Management Systems, Hotel

**Quality Assurance Systems** 

Spanish – Native, English – Advanced (CLB – 10), French – Intermediate (CLB – 7)

# **PROJECTS**

#### **TOOL SWAP**

**LANGUAGES** 

Web-based inventory tracking system that allows users to search for, reserve, add, edit, and delete items to share with their neighbours, as a share-tool library. Front-End: ReactJs, CSS - Back-End: NodeJs, Express, PostgreSQL.

#### PERN STACK CRUD APPLICATION TUTORIAL

A tutorial to develop an app that allows the user to see, add, update, and delete movies from a list. Front-End: HTML, CSS, React - Back-End: Node, Express, SQL.

#### **INTERVIEW SCHEDULER**

A scheduler that allows users to create, edit and delete interview appointments. Front-End: HTML, CSS, ReactJs - Back-End: Node, Express, SQL

Test: JEST, Storybook, Cypress.

#### **WIKIMAPS**

A web app that allows users to collaboratively create maps which list multiple "points".

Front-End: HTML, CSS - Back-End: Node, Express, SQL.

#### LIGHTHOUSE BNB

A clone of Airbnb. The app allows homeowners to rent out their homes to people on vacation. Back-End: Node, Express, SQL.

#### **TWEETER**

A single page Twitter clone. Front-End: HTML, CSS, Javascript - Back-End: jQuery, Ajax, Node, Express

Test: Mocha, Chai

# **EDUCATION**

Lighthouse Labs, Vancouver (B.C.). Jan. 2022 – Aug. 2022

**Diploma - Full Stack Web Development** 

Nebrija University, Madrid (Spain). 2016 - 2018 EUHT StPol, Barcelona (Spain). 2001 - 2004

College Diploma - Hotel Management

Master's Degree - Applied Linguistics: Teaching of Spanish

# **EMPLOYMENT**

Spanish teacher 2016 - 2022 2004 - 2015 Hotel Manager ◀ Assistant Manager

Casanovaspanish.com • MadVan Spanish School ◆ Vancouver, B.C. Accem ♦ Madrid, Spain

Facilitated acquisition of Spanish language and culture.

Created and edited materials for learning.

Performed functional business skills (financial, marketing, taxation) as a selfemployed.

Non-profit organization experience: data entry, managed student files and electronic records, compiled records and produced reports for the Government. AMResorts • Best Hotels ◆ Dominican Republic, Spain NH Hotels ♦ Haiti

Supervised operations Prepare budgets and forecasts. Controlled costs and payroll. Performed pre-opening activities. Conducted meetings. Resolved conflicts. Managed client relations.